Make way for Aladeen.
The Dictator is a comedy film directed by Larry Charles.
The heroic story of a dictator who risks his life to ensure that democracy
would never come to the country he so lovingly oppressed.
Aladeen / Efawadh, played by Sacha Baron Cohen.
Tamir, played by Ben Kingsley.
Zoey, played by Anna Faris.
Nadal, played by Jason Mantzoukas.
Omar, played by Sayed Badreya.
Maroush, played by Adeel Akhtar.
The Dictator is a 2012 political satire black comedy film directed by Larry Charles and
written by Sacha Baron Cohen, Alec Berg, David Mandel and Jeff Schaffer.
Baron Cohen, in the role of Admiral General Aladeen, the dictator of the fictional Republic of
Wadiya visiting the United States, stars alongside Anna Faris and Ben Kingsley.
Producers Jeff Schaffer and David Mandel said that Baron Cohen's character was inspired by real-life dictators with personality cults, such as Kim Jong Il of North Korea, Idi
Amin of Uganda, Colonel Muammar Gaddafi of Libya, Bokassa I of the Central African Empire, Mobutu Sese Seko of Zaire, and Saparmurat Niyazov of Turkmenistan.
Despite the Republic of Wadiya being located in real-life Eritrea, its own
dictator, Isaias Afwerki, was not referenced as inspiration.
The film's opening credits sarcastically dedicate it "in
loving memory" to Kim Jong Il, who died in 2011.
The Dictator was released on May 16, 2012, by Paramount
Pictures, and received mixed reviews from critics.
It was a box office success, grossing $190 million.
The film explores themes of petrol, culture
clash, dictator, coup d'etat, satire.
The tone is lighthearted.